# Philippine CHAMBAULT

Hollænderdybet 16, 2300 København, DENMARK (French-EU citizen, 37 yrs old)

□ (+45) 50 36 84 48 | ■ philippine.chambault@gmail.com | # pchambault.github.io/portfolio/ | □ pchambault | □ pchambault | Researchgate

## **Summary**\_

From international Academia to Private industry in Denmark, data enthusiast scientist with 12 yrs of experience specializing in statistical modelling and spatial analysis. **Programming in R** using large spatio-temporal and environmental datasets, I bring a strong statistical background and scientific rigour. While my background may be unconventional, it equips me with a unique perspective on data interpretation and problem-solving.

- **Strengths:** Structured (daily markdown reports), Writing & Reporting (secured €290,000 grant).
- Work Ethics: Deliver on time (carreful planning), Detail oriented & Meticulous (double-checking).
- Communication: Attended 13 conferences (3 awards), Translated science to non-specialists (3MT winner).
- Technical Skills: Statistical Modelling (proficient in R for 12 yrs), Data Visualization (Organized workshops).
- Ambition: Transition from Academia to the Industry to focus fully on data analysis while seeking an opportunity to contribute to a real-world impact in the Private sector.

## Work Experience \_\_\_\_\_

**Postdoctoral Researcher** Copenhagen - DENMARK

GRØNI ANDS NATURINSTITUT

2017,2020,Oct 2021-Present

- Predicted habitat loss for Arctic whales due to climate change using machine learning & telemetry data [random forest, BRT, neural network]
- Designed and calibrated a new biologging device to record physiological parameters from diving animals [engineering, protocol in captivity]
- Generated state space models showing the influence of sea temperatures on cold-adapted species in the Arctic whales [additive models]
- Developed a method to measure foraging success rate from acceleration and acoustic data [clustering, regression]

**Data Scientist** La Rochelle - FRANCE

AQUARIUM LA ROCHELLE

Jan 2021-Jul 2021

• Implemented statistical models to assess habitat suitability and survival probabilities [state space models, additive models]

**Data Scientist** Sète - FRANCE

FRENCH RESEARCH INSTITUTE FOR EXPLOITATION OF THE SEA

Nov 2018-Apr 2020

• Developed a methodological framework for predicting individual & population-level distributions to support decision-making [regression]

**Postdoctoral Researcher** Azores - PORTUGAL

University of the Azores

Apr 2018-Oct 2018

• Led geospatial analysis using satellite tracking & oceanographic data to investigate animal movement [regression, distance sampling]

#### **Education**

**PhD in Marine Ecology** Strasbourg - FRANCE

University of Strasbourg (French National Center for Scientific Research)

Jun 2014-Jun 2017

• I developed spatio-temporal models to identify how marine top predators use oceanographic features during migration

#### **MSc in Physical Oceanography & Marine Environments**

Paris - FRANCE

UNIVERSITY OF PIERRE ET MARIE CURIE (UPMC)

Sep 2011-Jun 2013

• Ecosystem Modelling, Functionning & Conservation: programming in R, ArcGIS and Matlab

### Skills

Writing Reporting (R Markdown, Quarto, LaTeX), Grant applications, Scientific papers (23 published, 17 as first author)

Languages French (native), English (fluent, TOEFL, been living in English-speaking countries for 5 yrs), Spanish (beginner)

**Programming** R studio, GitHub, ArcGIS

Communication Lectures & Workshops, Interviews, Plenary at conferences, 3Min Thesis winner, Supervised 8 MSc/PhD students

#### Interests

**Wildlife photography** Always been fascinated by nature, enjoy early mornings to catch the sunrise!

Horse riding Dressage & jumping for 8 yrs in competition, Attended the French Championships (2nd place in 2004)

Weekly practise to feel grounded, pause and find balance in my energetic life Yoga